Oppler, Alfred C.; Papers ger016
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers, 1946-1952; 3; 0.50 cubic ft.
  - Photograph of the Supreme Court Mission, 1950 (Box 3 (3-Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers), Folder 22)
  - Family Bureau, General Secretariat, Supreme Court of Japan, The Guide for the Family Court, ca. 1950 (Box 3 (3-Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers), Folder 23)
  - GHQ, SCAP, Selected Data on the Occupation of Japan, ca. 1950 (Box 3 (3-Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers), Folder 24)
  - Japanese Language Worksheets, ca. 1950 (Box 3 (3-Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers), Folder 25)
  - Oppler, "Report of the Supreme Court Mission", 1951 (Box 3 (3-Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers), Folder 26)
  - Oppler's Engagement Calendar, 1951 (Box 3 (3-Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers), Folder 27)
  - Oppler, Daily Activity Reports, 1951 (Box 3 (3-Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers), Folder 28)
  - Oppler, Weekly Work Summaries, Legislation and Justice Division, Undated (Box 3 (3-Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers), Folder 29)
  - "Final Briefings Presented to the Supreme Commander... Covering Portions of Occupation Duties", 1952 (Box 3 (3-Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers), Folder 30)
  - Photographs of Oppler with Japanese and American Officials, ca. 1952? (Box 3 (3-Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers), Folder 31)
  - Unidentified Photograph Taken in Japan, ca. 1952? (Box 3 (3-Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers), Folder 32)
  - Oppler's Awards and Citations, 1948-1952
- Far Eastern Command, G-5/J-5 Section, 1952-1957; 4; 0.075 cubic ft.
  This series consists of unpublished notes and opinions, photographs, and other documents Oppler created or collected while working as head of the Political and Legal Section of the Far Eastern Command. Of note is an autographed photograph of General Lyman L. Lemnitzer.
  - J-5 Briefing, ca. 1952 (Box 3 (4-Far Eastern Command, G-5/J-5 Section), Folder 33)
  - Office of Public Information, Republic of Korea, Constitution, ca. 1954 (Box 3 (4-Far Eastern Command, G-5/J-5 Section), Folder 34)
  - Oppler's Authorization to Visit Germany, 1955 (Box 3 (4-Far Eastern Command, G-5/J-5 Section), Folder 35)
  - Summary of Article on Foreign Influences on Japanese Law, 1955 (Box 3 (4-Far Eastern Command, G-5/J-5 Section), Folder 36)
  - Autographed Photograph of Colonel Louis M. Gosorn, 1955 (Box 3 (4-Far Eastern Command, G-5/J-5 Section), Folder 37)
  - Autographed Photograph of General Lyman L. Lemnitzer, ca. 1955 (Box 3 (4-Far Eastern Command, G-5/J-5 Section), Folder 38)
  - Oppler's Awards and Citations, 1957 (Box 3 (4-Far Eastern Command, G-5/J-5 Section), Folder 39)
  - Oppler's Awards and Citations, 1957
- United States Forces Japan, 1952-1959; 5; 0.15 cubic ft.
  This series consists of unpublished opinions, memoranda, official documents, photographs, and press summaries that Oppler generated or collected while serving as the International Relations Officer of the United States Forces Japan (USFJ). Of note are Oppler's "Personal Interest File", which contains clippings, USFJ memoranda and reports, and other documents concerning the affairs of Japan, Korea, and the Ryukyu Islands, and his file of clippings and documents concerning the Sunakawa case, which upheld the constitutionality of stationing United States troops in Japan.
  - Opinion Concerning Right of Assembly, 1958 (Box 3 (5-United States Forces Japan), Folder 40)
  - Autographed Photograph of Major General Paul Caraway, 1958 (Box 3 (5-United States Forces Japan), Folder 41)
  - Oppler's "Personal Interest Matter" File, 1958-1959 (Box 3 (5-United States Forces Japan), Folder 42)
  - Clippings, Press Summaries, and Memoranda Concerning the Sunakawa Case, 1959 (Box 3 (5-United States Forces Japan), Folder 43)
  - Oppler's Awards and Citations, 1959 (Box 3 (5-United States Forces Japan), Folder 44)
  - Inouye, "Historical Record of Federation of Japan Bar Association", 1959 (Box 3 (5-United States Forces Japan), Folder 45)
  - "Statement of General Lemnitzer... on the United States Land Policy in the Ryukyu Islands", ca. 1959? (Box 3 (5-United States Forces Japan), Folder 46)
  - Clippings, Press Summaries, and Memoranda Concerning the Sunakawa Case, 1959
  - Oppler's Awards and Citations, 1959
- Legal Reform in Occupied Japan, 1972-1977; 6; 0.15 cubic ft.
  This series contains documents generated in connection with Oppler's memoir, Legal Reform in Occupied Japan: A Participant Looks Back (Princeton University Press, 1976), including correspondence, reviews, and readers' notes. Of note are several typescript passages about life in Japan that were excised from the final version and a brief note from Supreme Court Justice William O. Douglas (October 23, 1974).
  - Autobiographical Passage Not Published in Legal Reform, ca. 1973 (Box 3 (6-Legal Reform in Occupied Japan), Folder 47)
  - Passages Not Published in Legal Reform, ca. 1973 (Box 3 (6-Legal Reform in Occupied Japan), Folder 48)
  - Chapter Not Published in Legal Reform, ca. 1973 (Box 3 (6-Legal Reform in Occupied Japan), Folder 49)
  - Editorial Guidelines, Jacket Copy, and Addresses of Recipients of Review and Complementary Copies, ca. 1973-1976 (Box 3 (6-Legal Reform in Occupied Japan), Folder 50)
  - Reviews of and Advertisements for Legal Reform, 1976-1977 (Box 3 (6-Legal Reform in Occupied Japan), Folder 51)
- Encyclopedia of Japan, ca. 1977-1982; 7; 0.075 cubic ft.
  This series contains documents generated in connection with Oppler's writing and editorial work for the Encyclopedia of Japan (Kodansha, 1980), among them Oppler's entries on the 1961 Sunakawa Case and the Japan-U.S. Security Treaties, an entry that he helped to content-edit, and an entry written by Kurt Steiner concerning Oppler's work in Japan. Also included are newsletters published by the staff of the Encyclopedia of Japan; the Spring 1979 issue contains a poem that Oppler wrote in praise of the project.
  - List of Legal Entries, Style Manual, and Newsletters, 1978-1980 (Box 3 (7-Encyclopedia of Japan), Folder 52)
  - Oppler's Entries on Sunakawa Case and U.S.-Japan Security Treaties, 1979 (Box 3 (7-Encyclopedia of Japan), Folder 53)
  - Entries by Ishimine, Sakai and Sakahara, and Steiner, 1979 (Box 3 (7-Encyclopedia of Japan), Folder 54)
- Miscellaneous Writings, 1948; 1960-1982; 8; 0.40 cubic ft.
  This series consists of correspondence, research notes, speech notes, and published and unpublished articles and essays that Oppler produced or gathered after his 1959 retirement and return to the United States.
  - Subseries 1: Correspondence, 1943-1981; 8.1; 0.05 cubic ft.
    This subseries contains correspondence with Thomas Blakemore, Kurt Steiner, Justin Williams, and other people Oppler worked with while in Japan. Other letters concern various interviews with scholars and journalists and various political causes that Oppler supported. Of note is a letter from Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Lyman L. Leminitzer (September 22, 1960). Oppler segregated almost all correspondence generated while working with the SCAP and the FEC and while writing Legal Reform in Occupied Japan and entries for The Encyclopedia of Japan and kept it with other papers pertaining to these activities. This arrangement has been preserved.
    - SCAP (Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers). General correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 1)
    - Alden, Jane, 1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 2)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1950-1980 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 3)
      (including Abortion issues).
    - Ando, Nisuke, 1969 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 4)
    - Arima, Chusabaro (Japan Federation of Bar Associations), 1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 5)
    - Bevis, Howard L. (Ohio State University), 1951-1952 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 6)
    - Blakemore, Thomas L., 1976-1979 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 7)
    - Brown, Richard G., 1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 8)
    - Byrne, Brendan T., 1978 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 9)
    - Caraway, Paul W., 1961; 1974 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 10)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Sanford Schwarz), 1943 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 11)
    - Carter, President Jimmy, 1980 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 12)
    - City of Norfolk, MacArthur Memorial, 1976-1977 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 13)
    - Coblenz, William A., 1950-1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 14)
    - Dach, Joseph, 1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 15)
    - Dando, Shigemitsu, 1974; 1979 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 16)
    - Danelski, David J., 1967 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 17)
    - David, René, 1951-1952 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 18)
    - Denver Journal of International Law and Policy, 1979 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 19)
    - deWetter, Louise, 1967 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 20)
    - Douglas, Justice William O., 1974 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 21)
    - Ehrenzweig, Albert A., 1949; 1967 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 22)
    - Encyclopedia of Japan (Takeshi Kokubo), 1978-1981 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 23)
    - Epstein, Fritz T., 1950-1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 24)
    - Fisher, Adrian S., 1950-1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 25)
    - Foley, Edward H., 1950 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 26)
    - Fraenkel, Ernst, 1943 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 27)
    - Friedrich, Carl J., 1949-1950 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 28)
    - Hall, Livingston, 1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 29)
    - Hays, Frank E., 1950 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 30)
    - Henderson, Dan F., 1978 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 31)
    - Herring, Pendleton, 1950 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 32)
    - Horitsu Jihu, 1972-1973 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 33)
    - Hozumi, Shigeto, 1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 34)
    - Inoue, Masahito, 1979-1981 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 35)
    - International Biographical Archives and Dictionary of Central European Emigrés, 1933-1945 (Harold A. Strauss), 1976-1979 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 36)
    - Jansen, Marius B., 1973 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 37)
    - Johnson, U. Alexis, 1952 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 38)
    - Kades, Charles L. (Hawkins, Delafield & Wood), 1950-1977 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 39)
    - Kobayashi, Justice Shunzo, 1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 40)
    - Koshi, George, 1977 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 41)
    - Lambie, Morris B., 1950 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 42)
    - Lemnitzer, General L. L., 1960 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 43)
    - Lochner, Louis P., 1967 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 44)
    - MacCoy, W. Pierce, 1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 45)
    - Mano, Judge Tsuyoski, 1951 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 46)
    - Martin, Charles E., 1950-1952 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 47)
    - Masui, Makoto, 1976 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 48)
    - Matsuo, Koya, 1974-1975 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 49)
    - Mendel, Douglas H., Jr., 1954 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 50)
    - Meyers, Howard, 1951-1952 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 51)
    - Moore, Paul D., 1973-1975 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 52)
    - Mori, Arthur K., 1951-1973 (Box 4 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 53)
    - Nemoto, Matsuo, 1970 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 1)
    - Neptune, Robert H., 1952 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 2)
    - New York Times (Letters to the Editor), 1970-1980 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 3)
    - Ochs, Reiko, 1975 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 4)
    - Okuyama, Hachiro, 1951 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 5)
    - Onuma, Yasuaki, 1976-1977 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 6)
    - Parker, James Perkins, 1951 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 7)
    - Peattie, Mark, 1975 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 8)
    - Physicians, 1969-1980 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 9)
    - Prescott, Stanley, 1947 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 10)
    - Princeton University Library, 1980 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 11)
    - Princeton University Press, 1974-1980 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 12)
    - Quigley, Harold S., 1949-1950 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 13)
    - Redford, Larry (Juris Publici), 1977-1980 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 14)
    - Reischauer, Edwin O., 1974-1977 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 15)
    - Rheinstein, Max, 1950-1951 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 16)
    - Rodino, Peter W. J., 1978 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 17)
    - Ruete, Hans Hellmuth, 1978 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 18)
    - Schenck, Hubert G., 1952 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 19)
    - Shimbum, Asahi, transcripts of interview with Oppler, 1971 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 20)
    - Snow, Conrad E., 1950-1951 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 21)
    - Sodei, Rinjiro, 1976 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 22)
    - Steiner, Kurt, 1950-1979 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 23)
    - Takemae, Eiji, 1981 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 24)
    - Tanaka, Haruhiko, 1951 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 25)
    - Tanaka, Hideo, 1977-1979 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 26)
    - Tanaka, Kotaro, 1952; 1972 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 27)
    - Tanaka, M., 1950 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 28)
    - Tate, Jack B., 1951 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 29)
    - TV Man Union, Inc. (Tokyo), 1981 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 30)
    - Unno, Shinkichi, 1953 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 31)
    - Ward, Robert E., 1973 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 32)
    - Washington Law Review (Milton D. Green), 1949-1978 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 33)
    - Williams, Harrison A., 1965; 1978 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 34)
    - Williams, Justin, Sr, 1970-1976 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 35)
    - Yamanaka, Toshio, 1974-1975 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 36)
    - Yasumura, Kazuo, 1973 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1943-1978 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 39)
    - Buchholz, Walther, 1941-1959; 1960-1969; 1970-1979 (Box 5 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 40-42)
      Buchholz, Walther.
  - Subseries 2: Articles and Speeches, 1961-1982; 8.2; 0.20 cubic ft.
    This subseries contains articles and speech notes Oppler wrote after retiring. Of particular interest are his analysis of the Sunakawa Case, in which the Japanese Supreme Court ruled that Japan's constitutional ban on rearmament did not prohibit the stationing of U.S. troops on Japanese soil, and notes for a speech that he gave a week before his death.
    - "The Sunakawa Case: Its Legal and Political Implications" (published), 1961 (Box 6 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 1)
    - Opinion on Israeli Law of Return (unpublished), ca. 1970? (Box 6 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 2)
    - Notes for "Sidelights on MacArthur's Occupation of Japan" Speech (unpublished), ca. 1972? (Box 6 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 3)
    - Oppler's Answers to Questions Posed by an Unknown Interviewer, ca. 1975? (Box 6 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 4)
    - "The Dutchess of Stone Pond" (unpublished), ca. 1978 (Box 6 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 5)
    - Articles for Juris Publici (University of Richmond Law School), 1979-1980 (Box 6 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 6)
    - Notes for "Great Decisions: Japan" Speech (unpublished) and Clippings, 1982 (Box 6 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3: Notes, 1948-1973; 8.3; 0.15 cubic ft.
    This subseries consists of research notes that Oppler wrote after his retirement; newspaper clippings, among them a 1948 issue of the Pacific Stars and Stripes, are sometimes interspersed. Some of Oppler's research may have been undertaken in preparation for the writing of Legal Reform in Occupied Japan: A Participant Looks Back, but some of the notes concern German and American law, society, and politics.
    - Notes and Clippings on MacArthur, Civil Liberties, Japan, Germany, and Vietnam, 1948-1973 (Box 6 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 8)
    - Notes on Prittie, Germans Against Hitler, ca. 1965 (Box 6 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 9)
    - Reading Notes on German, Japanese, and Korean Politics and Law, ca. 1966 (Box 6 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 10)
    - Notes on Dissertations and Books Concerning Japan, ca. 1970? (Box 6 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 11)
    - Notes on Japan Civil Liberties Union, Japanese Judiciary and Japanese Law, Undated (Box 6 (8-Miscellaneous Writings), Folder 12)
- Research Materials, 1944-1982; 9; 0.70 cubic ft.
  This series contains materials that Oppler received from colleagues, gathered while at various Asian studies conferences, or kept for their informational value.
  - Subseries 1: Presentation Copies, 1961-1980; 9.1; 0.05 cubic ft.
    This subseries contains inscribed copies of published and unpublished articles written by Kurt Nadelmann, Ulrich Mache, and Josef Derbolav, all of whom apparently met Oppler before 1939, Marius Jansen, Kurt Steiner, and Justin Williams, all of whom worked with Oppler in Japan, and Nitsuke Ando, whom Oppler evidently met while; residing in Japan.
    - Nadelmann, "Das Minderheitsvotum in Kollegialgericht --Bekanntgabe oder Geheimhaltung ?" (published), 1961 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 13)
    - Steiner, "Popular Political Participation and Political Development in Japan: The Local Level" (unpublished), ca. 1965 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 14)
    - Mache, "Die Überwindung des Amadisromans durch Andreas Heinrich Bucholtz" (published), 1966 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 15)
    - Jansen, "Japan Looks Back" (published), 1968 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 16)
    - Ando, "A Critical Appraisal of the Tokyo District Court's Decision on the Suikosha Case" (published), ca. 1968 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 17)
    - Derbolav, Essay in Pädagogik im Selbstdarstellung (published), 1976 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 18)
    - Williams, "What the Japanese Are Like" (unpublished), 1980 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 19)
  - Subseries 2: Conference Documents, 1961-1980; 9.2; 0.25 cubic ft.
    This subseries consists of materials that Oppler collected while attending various conferences concerning the study of Japan. Of particular interest are numerous unpublished papers concerning various aspects of Japanese law.
    - Harvard University Japanese-American Program for Cooperation in Legal Studies, Papers, 1961 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 20-22)
    - Princeton University Conference on the New Japan: Prospects and Promise, Participant List and Papers, 1962 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 23)
    - Twenty-Eighth American Assembly on the United States and Japan, Final Report, 1965 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 24)
    - Eleventh Southern Assembly on the United States and Japan, Papers, 1966 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 25)
    - Amherst College International Conference on the Occupation of Japan, Orientation Materials, Participant List, and Two Papers, 1980 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 26)
  - Subseries 3: Articles and Reference Works, 1944-1982; 9.3; 0.40 cubic ft.
    This subseries contains articles, pamphlets, and clippings that Oppler kept because of their informational value. Oppler may have gathered the earliest documents in thissubseries, which consist of newspaper articles concerning France, Germany, Japan, and Poland during the final years of the Second World War, in connection with his work for the United States Economic Administration and the Department of War. All of the other documents in this subseries were collected after his 1959 return to the United States. Some of these materials may have been assembled in preparation for the writing of Legal Reform in Occupied Japan.
    - Clippings Concerning France, Germany, Japan, and Poland, 1944-1945 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 27)
    - Japan Times Clippings, 1960 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 28)
    - Texts of Japan-U.S. Treaty and Security Agreements, 1960 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 29)
    - Japan Commission on the Constitution, Papers [fragment], 1961 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 30)
    - Kublin, What Shall I Read on Japan (published), 1961 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 31)
    - Kublin, Useful Japanese (published), 1961 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 32)
    - Overton, Travel in Japan (published), 1961 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 33)
    - Japanese-American Program for Cooperation in Legal Studies, "An Index to Japansese Law" (unpublished), 1961 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 34)
    - Law Firm of Stitt and Hemmendinger, "Okinawa" (unpublished), 1962 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 35)
    - Danielski, "The Supreme Court of Japan: An Exploratory Study" (unpublished), 1966 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 36)
    - Stein, "Common-Law Marriage: Its History and Certain Contemporary Problems" (published), 1969 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 37)
    - Jansen, "Japan and the United States" (unpublished), ca. 1969 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 38)
    - Unidentified Article on Japanese Law (published) and Clipping on Japan's Environmental Problems, 1970 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 39)
    - Abegglin, Kahn, and Morley, Japan and the United States in the 1970s (published) (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 40)
    - Steiner, Book Review (published) and Two Short Articles (unpublished), 1974-ca. 1975 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 41)
    - Association for Asian Studies, Doctoral Dissertations on Asia (published), 1975 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 42)
    - Committee on Asian Law, Association for Asian Studies, A Directory of Persons Interested in Asian Law (published), 1975 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 43)
    - State of New York, Court on the Judiciary, In re Waltemeade (unpublished), 1975 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 44)
    - Anderson, trans., The Law Partially Amending the Foreign Exchange and Foreign Trade Control Law (published), 1979 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 45)
    - Hollerman, "International Economic Controls in Occupied Japan" (published), 1979 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 46)
    - Masami, "Postwar Japanese Law and Legal Studies" (published), 1979 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 47)
    - Moore, "Reflections on the Occupation of Japan" (published), 1979 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 48)
    - Kawashima, "The Japanese Linguistic Consciousness and the Law" (published) and Letter from Marius Jansen, 1979-1980 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 49)
    - Vogel, "The Miracle of Japan" (published) and Letter to the New York Times, 1979-1981 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 50)
    - Japanese Press Summaries and Clippings, 1979-1982 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 51)
    - Materials By and About Justin Williams (published), 1980 (Box 6 (9-Research Materials), Folder 52)